Alfred I. Hallowell Papers 1892-1981 Mss.Ms.Coll.26
American Philosophical Society
- Series VI - Photographs
  - Subseries F. Miscellaneous Native American, [1920s-1952, n.d.]; Copy (353 photos)
    - [Ojibwa?], Fishing Lake, [1930s]; F203
    - [Ojibwa?], Fishing Lake, Left -- Nut Lake headman Right -- Chief Cole, Ramsack, [1930s]; F204
    - Fishing Lake, 1928; F205
    - [Ojibwa?], Fishing Lake, [1930s]; F206
    - [Ojibwa?], Fishing Lake, 1928; F207
      Pow-wow tent
    - [Ojibwa?], Fishing Lake, [1930s?]; F208
    - [Ojibwa?], Fishing Lake, [1930s?]; F209
    - Fort Alexander, left to right: Serges Bruyere, John Thompson, Duncan, 1938; F210
      Anderson, & John James Star standing before old log treaty house
      Photographer: W.H. Rand
    - Fort Alexander, [1938?]; F211
      Mission Church
    - Fort Alexander, 1938; F212
      Treaty
      See also: F215
    - Fort Alexander, [1938]; F213
      Grave yard -- Protestant
    - Fort Alexander, [1938]; F214
      13 children of Bear family -- Protestant
    - Fort Alexander, 1938; F215
      See also: F212
    - [Ojibwa?], Hollow Water River, Summer, 1931; F216
      Smoking fish and meat
    - [Ojibwa?], Hollow Water River, Summer, 1931; F217
      View from `Point" where summer camps are put up to avoid mosquitoes in "bush" *
    - [Ojibwa?], Hollow Water River, "Whiskeyjack", Summer, 1931; F218
    - [Ojibwa?], Hollow Water River, 1930; F219
      See also: F220, F221
    - [Ojibwa?], Hollow Water River, 1930; F220
      See also: F219, F221
    - [Ojibwa?], Hollow Water River, McPherson, Clerk, and Mountie, 1930; F221
      See also: F219, F220
    - Ojibwa, Hollow Water River Jack Head [?], Adolphus Sinclair and wife, 1931 1934 [?]; F222
      [From a trip to Saskatchewan, plains] -- J. Brown
    - Ojibwa, Hollow Water River Jack Head [?], 1931 1934 [?]; F223
      Crowd in front of Joe Peoples' tent
    - Ojibwa, Hollow Water River Jack Head [?], Peter Peoples, 1931 1934 [?]; F224
      See also: F225
      With old [midewiwin?] post and scared stone [From a trip to Saskatchewan, plains?] -- J. Brown
    - Ojibwa, Hollow Water River Jack Head [?], Peter Peoples, 1931 1934 [?]; F225
      With bear skull
      See alsp: F224
    - Ojibwa, Hollow Water River, 1931 1934 [?]; F226
      Peter Peoples wife & cow in corrall
    - Hollow Water River, 1931; F227
    - Cree, Island Lake, Farrington & Tom Evans, 1930; F228
      At camp en route
    - [Ojibwa?], Red Lake, Ont. [Lake Winnipeg Region], [1930s]; F229
      Photographer: Fryer's Studio (Fort William)
    - [Ojibwa?], [Lake Winnipeg Region?], [1930s]; F230
    - [Ojibwa?], Trout Lake, Ont. [Lake Winnipeg Region], [1930s]; F231
    - [Cree?] -- J. Brown 2/96, [Lake Winnipeg Region], [1930?]; F232
      See also: C66
    - [Ojibwa?], [Lake Winnipeg Region], [1930?]; F233
      Migrants of Trout [Lake] to Gods [Lake] -- pipikwachus [sp?]
    - [Ojibwa?], Gods [Lake] [Lake Winnipeg Region], [1930?]; F234
    - [Lake Winnipeg Region], [1930?]; F235
    - Cree [Ojibwa?], Grand Rapids, 1930; F236
      [From] boat
    - Cree [Ojibwa?], Norway House, Cross Lake, or Grand Rapids, 1930; F237
    - Cree [Ojibwa?], Norway House, Cross Lake, or Grand Rapids, 1930; F238
    - Cree [Ojibwa?], Norway House, Cross Lake, or Grand Rapids, 1930; F239
    - Cree [Ojibwa?], Norway House, Cross Lake, or Grand Rapids, 1930; F240
      [?] Mission
    - Ojibwa, Jack Head, 1934; F241
    - [Ojibwa?], [From a trip to Saskatchewan, plains?] -- J. Brown, J. Big Wind, Summer, 1931; F242
      See also: F243, F244
    - [Ojibwa?], [From a trip to Saskatchewan, plains?] -- J. Brown, J. Big Wind, Summer, 1931; F243
      See also: F242, F244
    - [Ojibwa?], [From a trip to Saskatchewan, plains?] -- J. Brown, J. Big Wind, Summer, 1931; F244
      See also: F242, F243
    - Mandan, [1930s] [1940?]; F245
      Village
      See also: F246, F247
    - Mandan, [1930s]; F246
      See also: F245, F247
    - Mandan, [1930s] [1940?]; F247
      See also: F245, F246
    - Mashpee, [Mass.], [1920?]; F248
    - Mashpee, Mashpee, [Mass.], [1920?]; F249
    - Manitou Rapids [near Barwick, Ont.?], Summer, 1931; F250
    - Manitou Rapids [near Barwick, Ont.?], Summer, 1931; F251
    - Manitou Rapids [near Barwick, Ont.?], Summer, 1931; F252
    - Manitou Rapids [near Barwick, Ont?], Summer, 1931; F253
    - [Ojibwa?], Manitou Rapids, F254
      Dance costume Rainy River -- Ojibwa Manitou Reserve near Barwick, Ont., U.S. & Canada
    - Montagnais, [1920s?]; F255
    - Ojibwa, Hallow Water River Jack Head, Morning Star, 1931 1934 [?]; F256
      See also: F257
      [Member of the Hole River Band who died in 1932. He was the last member of the Midewiwin on Lake Winnipeg.]
    - Ojibwa, [Hallow Water River?] [Jack Head?], Morning Star, 1931 1934 [?]; F257
      See also: F256
    - Nipissing, September, 1927; F258
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [Anna Panadis], [1920s]; F259
      See also: E58, E59, F13
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [Doris Dauphinais], July, 1922; F260
      See also: E126, E127, E128, F6
    - [Abnaki], St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., F261
    - [Abnaki], St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Alexander P. & Juliette L. Wawanolette, F262
    - [Abnaki], St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s?]; F263
    - [Abnaki], St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s?]; F264
    - [Abnaki], St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s?]; F265
    - [Abnaki], St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s?]; F266
    - [Abnaki], St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s?]; F267
    - [Abnaki], St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s?]; F268
    - [Abnaki], St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1943?]; F269
      From: Robert Ritzenthaler 3/13/43 #50110
      See also: F270, F271
      - Abenaki man, [1943?]
    - [Abnaki], St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1943?]; F270
      From: Robert Ritzenthaler 3/13/43 #50111
      See also: F269, F271
    - [Abnaki], St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1943?]; F271
      From: Robert Ritzenthaler 3/13/43
      See also: F269, F270
    - [Ojibwa?], Sweet Grass [or] Hobbema, Summer, 1931; F272
      See also: F273
    - [Ojibwa?], Sweet Grass [or] Hobbema, Summer, 1931; F273
      See also: F272
    - [Ojibwa?], Sweet Grass [or] Hobbema, Summer, 1931; F274
    - [Ojibwa?], Sweet Grass [or] Hobbema, Summer, 1931; F275
    - [Ojibwa?], Sweet Grass [or] Hobbema, Summer, 1931; F276
      See also: F286
    - [Ojibwa?], Sweet Grass [or] Hobbema, Summer, 1931; F277
      See also: F290, F292, F293
    - [Ojibwa?], Summer, 1931; F278
    - [Ojibwa?], Summer, 1931; F279
    - [Ojibwa?], Summer, 1931; F280
    - [Ojibwa?], Summer, 1931; F281
    - [Ojibwa?], Summer, 1931; F282
    - [Ojibwa?], Summer, 1931; F283
    - [Ojibwa?], Summer, 1931; F284
    - Ojibwa, [William Berens], Summer, 1931; F285
      See also: A8, A9, A10, A11, A12, A13,*
    - [Ojibwa?], Summer, 1931; F286
      See also: F276
    - [Ojibwa?], Summer, 1931; F287
    - [Ojibwa?], Sweet Grass [or] Hobbema, [Summer, 1931?]; F288
    - [1930s], F289
    - [Ojibwa?], [Sweet Grass or Hobbema], [Summer, 1931]; F290
      See also: F277, F292, F293
    - [Ojibwa?], Sweet Grass [or] Hobbema, [Summer, 1931]; F291
    - [Ojibwa?], [Sweet Grass or Hobbema], [Summer, 1931]; F292
      See also: F277, F290, F293
    - [Ojibwa?], [Sweet Grass or Hobbema], [Summer, 1931]; F923
      See also: F277, F290, F292
    - [Ojibwa?], Sweet Grass [or] Hobbema, [Summer, 1931; F294
    - [Ojibwa?], Sweet Grass [or] Hobbema Little Pine, H.S. Hughes-Caley, [1930s]; F295
    - [Ojibwa?], Sweet Grass [or] Hobbema Little Pine, [1930s]; F296
    - [Ojibwa?], Sweet Grass [or] Hobbema Little Pine, Solomon, [1930s]; F297
    - [Ojibwa?], Sweet Grass [or] Hobbema Little Pine, Louis, [1930s]; F298
    - [Ojibwa?], Sweet Grass [or] Hobbema Little Pine, Easter, [1930s]; F299
    - 1925, F300
      Tete de Boule
      Photographer: J.M. Cooper
      See also: F301, F302, F303, F304, F305
    - 1925, F301
      See also: F300, F302, F303, F304, F305
    - 1925, F302
      See also: F300, F301, F303, F304, F305
    - 1925, F303
      See also: F300, F301, F302, F304, F305
    - 1925, F304
      See also: F300, F301, F302, F303, F305
    - 1925, F305
      See also: F300, F301, F302, F303, F304
    - Abnaki [?] [Mohegan?], [1920s?]; F306
    - F307
      #2157 American Indian #5 Skeleton of an Arikara Indian University of South Dakota Museum
    - [Abnaki?], [St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q.?], [1920s?]; F308
      Abenaki #4
    - [1920s?], F309
    - F310
      Films S.W. Fondi -- Garden
    - Lac des Mills -- Near Savanne, Ont., F311
      Indian Cemetery
    - [Ojibwa?], Little Grand Rapids, [1930s?]; F312
      Indian Cemetery -- There are 2 to 5 graves under each tent
    - [1930s?], F313
    - Ojibwa, Onamia, Minn, August, 1945; F314
      A "dodoism" on a grave on an Indian reservation. The animal seems to be a lynx.
      Photographer: S.A. Sieber, S.V.D.
    - Ojibwa, Crow Portage, Ont., Summer, 1945; F315
      A [dream?] painted on a drum by an Ojibwa woman
    - Eskimo, Mouth of the MacKenzie River, F316
    - F317
      Original photograph: Smithsonian Institution, neg. #44388-H #492520 90a *
    - F318
      Indian hand puppet "Rain-on-the-Face" ca. 1890, Made in Lano family, Artist: David Ramage #492520 91a *
    - F319
      Original photograph: Smithsonian Institution, neg. #303 #492520 89a *
    - F320
      #492520 94a
      From: H.E. Laryfer Co., Inc. *
    - F321
      Original photograph: Smithsonian Institution, neg. # #492520 92a *
    - F322
      Original photograph: Smithsonian Institution, neg. # #492520 93a *
    - F323
      Original: From "A Pictorial History of the United States" by S.G. Goodrich, Philadelphia, 1845 *
    - F324
      Original photograph: Smithsonian Institution, neg. # #492520 88a *
    - F325
      Original photograph: Smithsonian Institution, neg. # #492520 96a *
    - F326
      R. 59 -- Hallowell dupl. file From Ser. III, The Backwash of the Frontier
    - F327
      Original photograph: Smithsonian Institution, neg. # #492520 95a *
    - F328
      15-8341 From Ser. V, Nets and Netting -- Northwest Coast
      #s on back of original photograph
    - F329
      15-8342
      From Ser. V, Nets and Netting -- Northwest Coast
    - F330
      1. III L. 194 -- Net needle, Algonquin. Collected by H.C. Cooke, Abittibi, Sept. 30, 1915; 2. III L. 142 -- Net needle, *
    - F331
    - Ojibwa, Lac du Flambeau, F332
      From Ser. V, Ojibwa Indian (Flambeau)
    - Ojibwa, 1915; F333
      Beaded woman's hood-cap, Lake Tewaggwin [sp?], Bear Island H.B. Post *
    - F334
      From Ser. V, Pottery
      See also: F335
      Photographer: B.L. Photographers
    - F335
      See also: F334
    - F336
      1. IV. E. 482 -- Ivory gage, carved Alaskan Eskimo. Collected by Fr. Mercier, Norton Sound to Pt. Barrow, 1886; 2. IV.
    - F337
      1. IV. E. 172 -- Shuttle with string, Alaskan Eskimo. Collected by Fr. Mercier, mouth of Yukon River, 1886; 2. IV. E. 318 --
    - [Abnaki], [St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q.], F338
      Photographer: E.L. Merrow Studio
      From Ser. V, [St. Francis Indian Reservation & other materials]
    - F339
      From Ser.V, Abenaki Indians -- Hunting Territories & Family Names
    - Abnaki, Carrie Miller, F340
      Photographer: Ettlin (New York)
      See also: E22
    - [Ojibwa?], Flatstone, Grand Rapids, 1933 [Date obtained?]; F341
      Obtained from son Lenk [sp?] -- medicine attached tobacco inside Photograph of scroll #10
    - [Ojibwa?], Flatstone, Grand Rapids, 1933 [Date obtained?]; F342
    - [Ojibwa?], Flatstone, Grand Rapids, 1933 [Date obtained?]; F343
    - [Ojibwa?], Flatstone, Grand Rapids, 1933 [Date obtained?]; F344
    - [Ojibwa?], Bluffhead, Grand Rapids, 1933 [Date obtained?]; F345
      Obtained from widow
      Photograph of scroll #8
    - [Ojibwa?], Bluffhead, Grand Rapids, 1933 [Date obtained?]; F346
    - [Ojibwa?], Bluffhead, Grand Rapids, 1933 [Date obtained?]; F347
    - [Ojibwa?], Bluffhead, Grand Rapids, 1933 [Date obtained?]; F348
    - Ojibwa, Grand Rapids, 1932 [Date obtained?]; F349
      From John Keeper
      From Oversized Folder #1
    - [Ojibwa?], [Berens River Region?], [1930s -- Date obtained?]; F350
    - [Ojibwa?], [Berens River Region?], [1930s -- Date obtained?]; F351
    - [Ojibwa?], [Berens River Region?], [1930s -- Date obtained?]; F352
    - [Ojibwa?], [Berens River Region?], [1930s -- Date obtained?]; F353
  - Subseries G. Personal and professional, 1890s-1971, n.d.; Original (ca. 122 photos and 15 negs., some photos in O.S. folder 10)
    Contains photographs and negatives of Hallowell and his family, items that removed from other series, and from research on the cultures of Africa, the Americas and Europe. It is currently unprocessed.
    Subseries G contains photographs removed from the following folders:
    Series I: Darnell, Regna
    Fernberger, Samuel W.
    Kutsche, Paul
    Macklin, Barbara June
    Zeller, Edith Valentine
    Series II: Nigeria
    Series III: "Personality in Primitive Society as Approached Through Rohrschach Techniques" Folder #1
    "Pigeon River People"
    Series V: Pictographs
  - Subseries H. Etruscan Art Album, n.d.; Original: 1 album
    Contains postcards depicting ruins, statues, sculpture, and murals from Volterea, Florence, and Rome. Several pictures include manuscript notes taken from readings of Dennis. Not individually catalogued.
  - Subseries I. Mexico Album, 1931, n.d.; Original: 1 album
    Contains postcards and clippings of ruins and sculpture from Chichen Itza, Uxmal, and Mitla. Not individually catalogued.
  - Subseries J. [New Mexico, Arizona Album]., n.d.; Original: 1 album
    Contains mostly postcards and some photographs of Native American people and culture. Some negatives for the photographs may be found in Subseries G. Not individually catalogued.
- Oversize: Series I-VI
  Oversized
  - Berens River maps, topographical info. on Lake Pekangekum Settlement, Saulteaux bands (Oversize 1, Folder 1)
    - Salteaux bands hunting territories., 1 map; 28 x 38 cm.
  - "Tabulation of Aggressive Acts," #1,#2,#3, (3 pieces) (Oversize 1, Folder 2)
  - [Tubulations of psychological data;] 4 pieces, including "Signs of Adjustment," "Neurotic Signs in Rorschach Protocols," "Neurotic Signs - Series A" (Inland Group, Lakeside Group), "Neurotic Signs in Rorschach Protocols of Berens River Saulteaux" (Oversize 1, Folder 3)
  - [Tabulatons of psychological data;], 6 pieces (Oversize 1, Folder 4)
  - [Tabulations of psychological data;] 9 pieces, including "Summary of Adults Protocols" (Lakeside, and Inland Bands) - Berens River Saulteaux. [Chart of date and locations of informant sources in Wisconsin, Minnesota, and Michigan;], 2 pieces (Oversize 1, Folder 5)
  - [Tabulations of psychological data (Ojibwa);], 6 pieces (Oversize 1, Folder 6)
  - [Tabulations of psychological data;] 4 pieces, including "Grand Totals" (Oversize 1, Folder 7)
    (Berens River)
  - [Tabulations of psychological data;], 18 pieces (Oversize 1, Folder 8)
  - "Genealogical Chart No. 1" (Oversize 1, Folder 9)
  - "Indian (B.R.) Photographs" and [unidentified.], 12 pieces. (Oversize 1, Folder 10)
    These are enlarged copies from Series VI Subseries A and F including A10, A122 (3 copies), A207, A230, and F63.
- Extra Oversized Folders
  - Printed maps with manuscript annotations; all published by the Department of the Interior, Canada: (Oversize X1, Folder 1)
    - 1. Ontario & Quebec. Cornwall Sheet., 1929
    - 2. Quebec. Chibougamau sheet., 1922
    - 3. Quebec. La Tuque Sheet., 1928
    - 4. Quebec. Mont Lauvier Sheet., 1928
    - 5. Quebec. Montreal Sheet., 1930
    - 6. Quebec. Quebec Sheet., 1929
    - 7. Quebec. Roberval Sheet., 1929
  - Genealogical charts: 2 marked "Genealogical Chart No. 2," and one Grand Rapids population (demographic) chart (Oversize X1, Folder 2)
  - Genealogical/population charts; 13 pieces. Includes Grand Rapids, Pekangikum, Berens River demographic data (Oversize X1, Folder 3)
  - Population/Residence (?) charts; 4 pieces. Demographic data (Oversize X1, Folder 4)
  - Genealogical charts: "Genealogical Chart No. 1," "Genealogical Chart No. 2," and one chart of demographic data marked "Flambeau" (Oversize X1, Folder 5)
  - Misc.: Indian drawings - illustrations of?, on scrolls (?); misc. unidentified (Oversize X1, Folder 6)